Connecticut Citizens Action Group Records 1987.0024
Archives and Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library
Connecticut Citizens Action Group Records
undated, 1964-2002
Archives and Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library
1987.0024
150.8 Linear Feet
The Connecticut Citizen Action Group was the first state-based consumer interest group. Created in 1971 by Ralph Nader and directed by Toby Moffett, CCAG was designed to represent, inform, unite, and empower the citizens of Connecticut in their roles as consumers, workers, tax payers, and voters. Taking on such issues as illegal business practices, utility rate increases, environmental pollution, and consumer fraud, the newly formed group was inundated with citizen requests for information and counsel. Among its major activities and accomplishments are: the General Assembly Project, an in-depth analysis of the behavior of state legislators; the Health Project, which compiled a wide range of state health care information; organizing efforts to enact the Bottle Bill, which required deposits on many types of beverage containers; enforcing environmental standards and enacting consumer protection legislation; and watchdog oversight and legal action concerning utility companies and development projects.
Access
The collection is open and available for research.
Acquisition Information
The records of the Connecticut Citizen Action Group were donated to the Historical Manuscripts and Archives Division of the University of Connecticut Libraries in December of 1980. Since then, additional materials have been added.
Arrangement
Series I: Director's Records (undated, 1974-1985) contain the files of the directors of CCAG, arranged alphabetically by topic.
Series II: Press Releases and Public Information (undated, 1972-1986) includes information collected and distributed the media on topics of interest to its members.
Series III: Administrative Files (undated, 1972-1984) contains general administrative records pertaining to the running of the origanization not specifically associated with a director.
Series IV: Member Groups (undated, 1970-1984) contains information about or concerning the establishment and operation of regional groups and organzations.
Series V: Gubernatorial Project (undated, 1967-1980) contains records about Connecticut governors.
Series VI: General Assembly Project (undated, 1967-1979) contains information, reports, and questionnaires by and about members of the Connecticut General Assembly.
Series VII: Health Project (undated, 1962-1980) contains information, reports, correspondence, publications and grants pertaining to health issues.
Series VIII: North Haven Mall (undated, 1978-1984) includes documents relevant to the development of a mall in North Haven.
Series IX: Bottle Bill (undated, 1969-1978) documents organizational activites, research and background associated with the passage of the Connecticut Bottle Bill.
Series X: Mary Mushinsky Files (undated, 1973-1979) include the files associated with Mary Mushinsky.
Series XI: Environmental Issues (undated, 1971-1985) includes such topics as conservation, energy, fuels, hazardous waste, pollution, housing, and legislation.
Series XII: Energy Issues (undated, 1964-1982) includes correspondence, reports, studies, plans and materials associated with various forms of energy resources, production and distribution at the local, state and national level.
Series XIII: Utility Rate Cases (undated, 1970-1990s) includes information, files, reports, studies and legal materials pertaining to power companies operating in Connecticut and relevant information from other states.
Series XIV: Consumer Issues (undated, 1971-1979) includes files on issues pertaining to consumer concerns and complaints.
Series XV: Lobbying Efforts (undated, 1977-1984) contains information, files, and correspondence associated with CCAG lobbying.
Series XVI: Subject Files (undated, 1969-1983) contains files on topics of interest to the organization including taxes, utilities, insurance, economics and labor.
Series XVII: 1992 Addition (undated, 1970-1990) contains materials added to the collection in 1992.
Series XVIII: 1999 Addition (undated, 1970-1998) contains materials added to the collection in 1999.
Series XIX: 2006 Addition (undated, 1987-2002) contains materials added to the collection in 2006.
Series XX: 2013 Addition (undated, 1990-2010) contains materials added to the collection in 201306.
History
The Connecticut Citizen Action Group was the first state-based consumer interest group. Created in 1971 by Ralph Nader and directed by Toby Moffett, CCAG was designed to represent, inform, unite, and empower the citizens of Connecticut in their roles as consumers, workers, tax payers, and voters. Taking on such issues as illegal business practices, utility rate increases, environmental pollution, and consumer fraud, the newly formed group was inundated with citizen requests for information and counsel. One year after its inception, CCAG created the Citizen's Lobby. The Lobby's purpose was to increase citizen participation in the legislative process, and to sharpen the awareness of legislators to the needs and demands of their constituents. Among its victories, Citizen's Lobby lists passage of legislation allowing substitution of generic prescription drugs; a ban on utilities charging ratepayers for utility advertising; the Environmental Policy Act, which requires the state to submit statements regarding the environmental impact of state projects; a toll-free hot line to the Department of Consumer Protection for citizen complaints and problems; consumer protection legislation concerning issues ranging from credit card interest charges to see-through meat packaging; and protection of thousands of acres of watershed lands. In 1975, CCAG instituted a canvassing program with a staff of community organizers to go into Connecticut neighborhoods, explain CCAG's work, and ask for financial and active support. This effort at community organizing tripled CCAG's budget by the end of its first decade and swelled membership from three thousand in the mid-1970s to twenty-eight thousand in the mid-1980s. CCAG has served for over thirty years as an advocate for the rights of Connecticut citizens. Among its major activities and accomplishments are: the General Assembly Project, an in-depth analysis of the behavior of state legislators; the Health Project, which compiled a wide range of state health care information; organizing efforts to enact the Bottle Bill, which required deposits on many types of beverage containers; enforcing environmental standards and enacting consumer protection legislation; and watchdog oversight and legal action concerning utility companies and development projects.
Scope and Content
The Connecticut Citizens Action Group Records document the activities and concerns of the first state-formed consumer interest group. Their records contain significant information about most of the major consumer and public interest issues of the 1970s and 1980s, ranging from environmental and energy concerns to health, housing, political reform, insurance, and housing. There are no restrictions on the use of these records. There are other additional records that were received after this guide was produces.
Medical care; Governors; Health insurance; Legislators; Housing; Voting; Law; Connecticut (state); Societies; Medicare; African Americans; Taxation; United States (nation); Product coding; Maps (documents); Audiotapes; Politicians; Administrative records; Personal papers; Correspondence; Labor unions; Political participation; Publications (documents); Voter registration; Citizens' associations; Air--Pollution; Mental health; Airport noise; Energy conservation; Lobbying; Women; Child care; Environmental law; Asbestos; Clippings (information artifacts); Pamphlets; Automobile industry and trade; Fliers (printed matter); Abortion; Consumers; Agricultural laborers; Civil rights; Automobiles--Safety measures; Press releases
- Series I: Director's Records, undated, 1974-1985
  - Marc Caplan Files
    - AAA (Box 1:, Folder 1)
    - Abate, Rep. Ernest (Box 1:, Folder 2)
    - Abortion (Box 1:, Folder 3)
    - Acorn (Box 1:, Folder 4)
    - Advertising Guide (Box 1:, Folder 5)
    - Aging, Department of (Box 1:, Folder 6)
    - Agriculture, Department of (Box 1:, Folder 7)
    - Air Pollution (Box 1:, Folder 8)
    - Airline Passenger Cargo (Box 1:, Folder 9)
    - Allegheny Airlines Complaints (Box 1:, Folder 10)
    - American Medical Association (Box 1:, Folder 11)
    - Antitrust (Box 1:, Folder 12)
    - Asbestos (Box 1:, Folder 13)
    - Attorney General (Box 1:, Folder 14)
    - Auto Repair (Box 1:, Folder 15)
    - Auto Safety Standards (Box 1:, Folder 16)
    - Banks (Box 1:, Folder 17)
    - Banking Department (Box 1:, Folder 18)
    - Blue Cross Dental Plan (Box 1:, Folder 19)
    - Blue Cross Testimony (Box 1:, Folder 20)
    - Blue Laws (Box 1:, Folder 21)
    - Bottle Bill (Box 1:, Folder 22)
    - Buzzuto, Richard (Senator) (Box 1:, Folder 23)
    - Broadcasting (Box 1:, Folder 24)
    - Cadrain, memoranda (Box 1:, Folder 25)
    - Campaign Reform (Box 1:, Folder 26)
    - Cancer Society (Box 1:, Folder 27)
    - Caucus (Box 1:, Folder 28)
    - Christian Conference of Connecticut (Box 1:, Folder 29)
    - Cities (Box 1:, Folder 30)
    - CAG, New Britain (Box 1:, Folder 31)
    - Citizens/Labor Energy Coalition (Box 1:, Folder 32)
    - Citizen Rule Making Petitions (Box 1:, Folder 33)
    - City and Town Development Act (Box 1:, Folder 34)
    - Civil Aeronautics Board (Box 1:, Folder 35)
    - Clothing Flammability (Box 1:, Folder 36)
    - Coin Campaign (Box 1:, Folder 37)
    - Commerce, Department of Environmental Affirmative Action (Box 1:, Folder 38)
    - Commission on Hospitals and Health Care (Box 1:, Folder 39)
    - Common Cause (Box 1:, Folder 40)
    - Community Affairs, Department of (Box 1:, Folder 41)
    - Community Renewal Team (Box 1:, Folder 42)
    - Conference on Alternative State and Local Policies (Box 1:, Folder 43)
    - Conflict of Interest (Box 1:, Folder 44)
    - Congress Watch, Organizing (Box 1:, Folder 45)
    - CT Association of Human Services (Box 1:, Folder 46)
    - CT Association for Community Action (CAFCA) (Box 1:, Folder 47)
    - CT Automotive Trades Association (Box 1:, Folder 48)
    - CT Citizen Research Group, Guilford (Box 1:, Folder 49)
    - CT Civil Liberties Union News (Box 1:, Folder 50)
    - CT Construction Industries Association (Box 1:, Folder 51)
    - CT Environmental Policy Act (Box 1:, Folder 52)
    - CT Hospital Association (Box 1:, Folder 53)
    - CT Public Service Council (Box 1:, Folder 54)
    - CT Transportation Authority (Box 1:, Folder 55)
    - Consumer Federation of America (CFA) (Box 2:, Folder 56)
    - CFA, United Auto Workers Consumer Conference (Box 2:, Folder 57)
    - Consumer Information (Box 2:, Folder 58)
    - Consumer Protection, Department of (Box 2:, Folder 59)
    - Consumer Protection Agency Bill (Box 2:, Folder 60-61)
    - Cooperative Bank Bill, National Consumer (Box 2:, Folder 62)
    - Cooperatives (Box 2:, Folder 63)
    - Corporate Reform (Box 2:, Folder 64)
    - Cotter, William (Representative) (Box 2:, Folder 65)
    - Court Reform (Box 2:, Folder 66)
    - Credit Cards (Box 2:, Folder 67)
    - Daycare (Box 2:, Folder 68)
    - Deaf and Hearing Impaired (Box 2:, Folder 69)
    - Democratic Party (Box 2:, Folder 70)
    - Dentistry
      - Consumer Guides (Box 2:, Folder 71)
      - General (Box 2:, Folder 72)
    - Direct Primary (Box 2:, Folder 73)
    - Disarmament Walk (Box 2:, Folder 74)
    - Dixon, Paul (FIC Commission) (Box 2:, Folder 75)
    - Doctor's Directory and Advertising (Box 2:, Folder 76)
    - Dodd, Christopher J. (Representative) (Box 2:, Folder 77)
    - Drugs
      - Consumer Guide, Rebuttal to CCAG (Box 2:, Folder 78)
      - General (Box 2:, Folder 79)
      - Prospective Purchaser Regulations (Box 2:, Folder 80)
      - Posting (Box 2:, Folder 81)
      - Senior Citizen Discount (Box 2:, Folder 82)
      - Soybel Case, Key Document (Box 2:, Folder 83)
      - Soybel Lawsuit (Box 2:, Folder 84)
    - Education Instruction (Box 2:, Folder 85)
    - Election of Remedies (Box 2:, Folder 86)
    - Emilson, Beth (Box 2:, Folder 87)
    - Energy (Box 3:, Folder 88)
    - Energy Coalition, Citizen Labor (Box 3:, Folder 89)
    - Energy Conservation (Box 3:, Folder 90)
    - Energy: Department of Consumer Advisory Panel (Folder 1 of 3) (Box 3:, Folder 91-93)
    - Environment (Box 3:, Folder 94)
    - Environmental Caucus (Box 3:, Folder 95)
    - Environmental Law (Box 3:, Folder 96)
    - Environmental Protection, Department of (Box 3:, Folder 97)
    - Environmentalists: Labor (Box 3:, Folder 98)
    - EPA Mileage Study, Hartford (Box 3:, Folder 99)
    - Escrow Accounts (Box 3:, Folder 100)
    - Filer Committee (Box 3:, Folder 101)
    - Financial Disclosure (Box 3:, Folder 102)
    - Food Quality and Safety (Box 3:, Folder 103)
    - Freedom of Information (Box 3:, Folder 104)
    - Gaffney Nomination (Box 3:, Folder 105)
    - General Assembly
      - Correspondence (Box 3:, Folder 106)
      - Full-Time (Box 3:, Folder 107)
      - Project (Box 3:, Folder 108-113)
      - Rating (Box 3:, Folder 114)
      - Traveling (Box 3:, Folder 115)
    - Giamo, Robert (Representative) (Box 3:, Folder 116)
    - Grasso Correspondence (Box 3:, Folder 117)
    - Grasso: Emergency Budget Proposals (Box 3:, Folder 118)
    - Greater Hartford Process (Box 3:, Folder 119)
    - Gubernatorial Profiles (Box 3:, Folder 120)
    - Guilford (Box 3:, Folder 121-122)
    - Gun Control (Box 3:, Folder 123)
    - Handicapped Citizen (Box 3:, Folder 124)
    - Hartford (Box 3:, Folder 125)
    - Hartford Garage (Box 3:, Folder 126)
    - Hartford Times Case (Box 3:, Folder 127)
    - Health (Box 3:, Folder 128-129)
    - Health Directory (Box 4:, Folder 130)
    - Health, National Health Planning Act, 1974 (Box 4:, Folder 131-132)
    - Health: Physician Incompetence (Box 4:, Folder 133)
    - Health Spas (Box 4:, Folder 134)
    - Highway Death Traps (Box 4:, Folder 135)
    - Hill Burton Act (Box 4:, Folder 136)
    - Homeowners (Box 4:, Folder 137)
    - Horvath Paper (Box 4:, Folder 138)
    - Hospital Care (Box 4:, Folder 139)
    - Hospital Guide (Box 4:, Folder 140-141)
    - Hovley, Robert (Senator) (Box 4:, Folder 142)
    - Housing
      - General (Box 4:, Folder 143)
      - Security Deposits (Box 4:, Folder 144)
    - Human Services Coalition (Box 4:, Folder 145)
    - Hunts Brook Chronology (Box 4:, Folder 146)
    - Indirect Sources (Box 4:, Folder 147)
    - Inflation
      - General (Box 4:, Folder 148)
      - White House Briefing (Box 4:, Folder 149)
    - Initiative Amendment (Box 4:, Folder 150-151)
    - Insurance Handbook (Box 4:, Folder 152)
    - Interventions (Box 4:, Folder 153)
    - Jai-Alai Investigation (Box 4:, Folder 154)
    - Judicial Review (Box 4:, Folder 155)
    - Justice, Administration of (Box 4:, Folder 156)
    - Kaszeta, Julie (Box 4:, Folder 157)
    - Kelman Libel Suit (Box 4:, Folder 158)
    - Kennelly, James (Representative) (Box 4:, Folder 159)
    - Killian, Robert (Lt. Governor) (Box 4:, Folder 160)
    - Labor: Full-Employment Coalition (Box 4:, Folder 161)
    - Landlord/Tenant (Box 4:, Folder 162)
    - Land Use (Box 4:, Folder 163)
    - Lead Poisoning (Box 4:, Folder 164-166)
    - League of Women Voters (Box 5:, Folder 167-168)
    - Legal Services
      - General (Box 5:, Folder 169-170)
      - "Bringing the Bar to Justice" (Box 5:, Folder 171)
      - Fee Schedules (Box 5:, Folder 172)
    - Legislative Commissioners (Box 5:, Folder 173)
    - Legislature (Box 5:, Folder 174-181)
    - Legislative News (Box 5:, Folder 182)
    - Legislative Reform (Box 5:, Folder 183)
    - License Renewal Challenge (Box 5:, Folder 184)
    - Lieberman, Joseph (Box 5:, Folder 185)
    - Liquor Issues (Box 5:, Folder 186)
    - Lloyd, Douglas (Box 5:, Folder 187)
    - Low Income Contracts (Box 5:, Folder 188)
    - Lottery (Box 5:, Folder 189)
    - Machinists, International Association of (Box 5:, Folder 190)
    - McKinney, Stewart (Representative) (Box 5:, Folder 191)
    - Middlebury, Uniroyal Property Tax (Box 5:, Folder 192)
    - Military Spending (Box 5:, Folder 193)
    - Moffett vs. Killian (Box 5:, Folder 194)
    - Morning After Pill (Box 5:, Folder 195)
    - Motor Vehicle Department (Box 5:, Folder 196)
    - Multi-Service Senior Citizen Center (Box 5:, Folder 197)
    - NAACP (Box 5:, Folder 198)
    - Nader and Groups (Box 5:, Folder 199)
    - National Advertising Review Board (Box 5:, Folder 200)
    - National Environmental Policy Act (Box 5:, Folder 201)
    - National Health Insurance (Box 5:, Folder 202)
    - National Peoples Action (Box 5:, Folder 203)
    - New England Congressional Caucus, Energy Conference (Box 5:, Folder 204)
    - New Haven (Box not specified)
      - General (Box 6:, Folder 205-206)
      - Girl's Recreation League (Box 6:, Folder 207)
      - Property Tax (Box 6:, Folder 208)
      - Water Company (Box 6:, Folder 209)
    - Noise Pollution (Box 6:, Folder 210)
    - Nuclear Power (Box 6:, Folder 211)
    - Nursing Homes (Box 6:, Folder 212)
    - Occupational Health (Box 6:, Folder 213)
    - Office of Urban Affairs, Archdiocese of Hartford (Box 6:, Folder 214)
    - Oil Refinery. Long Island Sound (Box 6:, Folder 215)
    - O'Neill, William (Representative) (Box 6:, Folder 216)
    - Open Heart Surgery (Box 6:, Folder 217)
    - Openness in Government (Box 6:, Folder 218)
    - People and Taxes (Box 6:, Folder 219)
    - Transportation (Box 6:, Folder 220)
    - Unemployment Compensation (Box 6:, Folder 221)
    - Uniroyal (Box 6:, Folder 222)
    - Unit Pricing (Box 6:, Folder 223)
    - United Aircraft, Contributions (Box 6:, Folder 224)
    - Unnecessary Surgery (Box 6:, Folder 225)
    - U.S. Congress (Box 6:, Folder 226)
    - Universal Product Code (Box 6:, Folder 227)
    - Utilities
      - Committee for Lower Bills (Box 6:, Folder 228)
      - Contacts (Box 6:, Folder 229)
      - Consumer Council (Box 6:, Folder 230)
      - Estimated Billing (Box 6:, Folder 231)
      - Northeast Utilities Rate Case, 1979 (Box 6:, Folder 232)
      - Northeast Utilities Variance Request (Box 6:, Folder 233)
      - Public Utilities Commission (Box 6:, Folder 234)
      - Settlements, 1974,1976 (Box 6:, Folder 235)
      - Shutoffs (Box 6:, Folder 236)
      - SNET Consumer Affairs Program (Box 6:, Folder 237)
      - SNET Consumer Case, 1977 (Box 6:, Folder 238)
      - United Illuminating Stock Sale and Rate Hike, 1978 (Box 6:, Folder 239)
    - Wallingford Citizens for Consumer Action (Box 6:, Folder 240)
    - Wallingford Reevaluation (Box 6:, Folder 241)
    - Water Pollution (Box 6:, Folder 242)
    - Weicker, Lowell (Senator) (Box 6:, Folder 243)
    - Workfare (Box 6:, Folder 244)
    - Workman's Compensation (Box 6:, Folder 245)
    - Zoning (Box 6:, Folder 246)
  - Miles Rappoport Files
    - AFL-CIO, 1981 November (Box 7:, Folder 247)
    - Association of Community Organizations for Reform Now (Box 7:, Folder 248)
    - All People's Congress (Box 7:, Folder 249)
    - American People's Heritage (Box 7:, Folder 250)
    - Americans For Common Sense (Box 7:, Folder 251)
    - Anderson, Marc (Box 7:, Folder 252)
    - Alternative State and Local Public Policies (Box 7:, Folder 253-255)
    - Banking (Box 7:, Folder 256)
    - Boyte, Harry (Box 7:, Folder 257)
    - California Tax Reform Association (Box 7:, Folder 258)
    - Citizen Action League (Box 7:, Folder 259)
    - Citizen Action League of New Britain (Box 7:, Folder 260)
    - Cape Cod Health Care (Box 7:, Folder 261)
    - Carolina Action (Box 7:, Folder 262)
    - Carolina Brown Lung Association (Box 7:, Folder 263)
    - Catholic Commission on Urban Ministry (Box 7:, Folder 264)
    - Caucus of Connecticut Democrats (Box 7:, Folder 265)
    - Center for Community Change (Box 7:, Folder 266)
    - Center for Connecticut's Future (Box 7:, Folder 267)
    - Center for Urban Policy Studies Ideas for Action (Box 7:, Folder 268)
    - Citizen's Alliance (Box 7:, Folder 269)
    - Chicago Northwest Organizing (Box 7:, Folder 270)
    - Chrysler Corporation Loan (Box 7:, Folder 271)
    - Citizens Action
      - General, 1979-1983 (Box 7:, Folder 272-282)
      - Affiliates Budgets (Box 7:, Folder 283)
      - Board (Box 7:, Folder 284)
      - Board Meeting (Box 7:, Folder 285-288)
      - Bylaws (Box 7:, Folder 289)
      - Conference, 1980 November 22 - 23 (Box 7:, Folder 290)
      - Meeting, 1981 January 5 (Box 7:, Folder 291)
      - Meeting, 1982 August 1 (Box 7:, Folder 292)
      - Meeting, 1982 September (Box 7:, Folder 293)
      - National Staff Meeting, 1983 December 8 (Box 7:, Folder 294)
      - Northeast Regional Conference, 1982 July 10 (Box 7:, Folder 295-296)
      - Organizing Committee (Box 7:, Folder 297-298)
      - Progressive Economic Program (Box 7:, Folder 299)
      - Staff Directory (Box 7:, Folder 300)
      - Staff Director's Meetings (Box 7:, Folder 301-303)
    - Citizens Against Nuclear War (Box 7:, Folder 304)
    - Citizens Heritage Center (Box 7:, Folder 305)
    - Citizens Lobby (Box 7:, Folder 306)
    - Citizens Party (Box 7:, Folder 307)
    - Citizens For Tax Justice (Box 7:, Folder 308)
    - Citizen/Labor Energy Coalition (Box 8)
      - General (Box 8:, Folder 309)
      - National (Box 8:, Folder 310-312)
    - Citizens Utility Board (Box 8:, Folder 313)
    - Coalition For Consumer Justice (Box 8:, Folder 314)
    - Coalition for a New Foreign and Military Policy (Box 8:, Folder 315)
    - "Cold War Liberalism", 1983 April (Box 8:, Folder 316)
    - Common Cause (Box 8:, Folder 317)
    - Community Jobs (Box 8:, Folder 318-321)
    - Community-Labor Alliance (Box 8:, Folder 322)
    - Community Labor Organizing Committee (Box 8:, Folder 323)
    - Connecticut Citizens Concerned with Convalescent Care (Box 8:, Folder 324)
    - Connecticut Council of Senior Citizens (Box 8:, Folder 325)
    - Connecticut Women's Congress, 2nd (Box 8:, Folder 326)
    - Congress Watch (Box 8:, Folder 327)
    - Connecticut Association for Human Services (Box 8:, Folder 328)
    - Connecticut Business Industry Association (Box 8:, Folder 329)
    - Connecticut Correctional Institutions (Box 8:, Folder 330)
    - Connecticut Elder, The (Box 8:, Folder 331)
    - Connecticut Environmental Caucus (Box 8:, Folder 332)
    - Connecticut Fund for the Environment (Box 8:, Folder 333)
    - ConnPirg (Box 8:, Folder 334)
    - Consumer Education (Box 8:, Folder 335)
    - Consumer Federation of America (Box 8:, Folder 336)
    - Co-op America (Box 8:, Folder 337)
    - COPE (Box 8:, Folder 338)
    - Critical Issues in Criminal Justice (Box 8:, Folder 339)
    - Democracy Project (Box 8:, Folder 340)
    - Democratic Agenda (Box 8:, Folder 341)
    - Democratic Left (Box 8:, Folder 342)
    - Democratic Socialists of America (Box 8:, Folder 343)
    - Democratic Socialist Organizing Committee (Box 8:, Folder 344-345)
    - Developer Agreements (Box 8:, Folder 346)
    - Disclosure (Box 8:, Folder 347)
    - Economic Rights Organization (Box 8:, Folder 348)
    - Electoral Act (Box 8:, Folder 349)
    - Elect (Box 8:, Folder 350)
    - Environmental Information (Box 8:, Folder 351)
    - Fair Budget Action Campaign (Box 8:, Folder 352)
    - Fund For a Democratic Majority (Box 8:, Folder 353)
    - Grassroots Organizing Book (Box 8:, Folder 354)
    - Hartford Areas (Box 8:, Folder 355)
    - Hartford Process (Box 8:, Folder 356)
    - Hayden, Tom (Box 8:, Folder 357)
    - Fund For Secure Energy, Inc. (Box 8:, Folder 358)
    - Homefront (Box 8:, Folder 359)
    - Housing (Box 8:, Folder 360)